WHO GET THAT RIGHT TO ME
AND I GLADLY STAND UP NEXT TO
YOU
AT THE HER STILL TODAY
BECAUSE THERE AIN'T NO DOUBT I
LOVE THIS LAND
GOD BLESS THE USA ♪ ♪
AND I'M PROUD TO BE AN AMERICAN
WHERE AT LEAST I KNOW I'M FREE
AND I WANT FORGET THE MEN WHO
DIED
WHO GET THAT RIGHT TO ME
AND I GLADLY STAND UP NEXT TO
YOU
AND DEFEND HER STILL TODAY
BECAUSE THERE AIN'T NO DOUBT I
LOVE THIS LAND
GOD BLESS THE USA ♪ ♪
PRES. TRUMP: THANK YOU VERY
MUCH.
TONY HAS BEEN A FRIEND OF MINE
FOR A LONG TIME, A GREAT GUY,
AND I WANT TO THANK TONY
ROBBINS.
THANK YOU OFFERED BEING HERE,
ONE OF THE MOST REVOLUTIONARY
PRODUCT LAUNCHES OF ALL TIME.
IT REALLY IS.
IT IS THE ULTIMATE, IT IS CALLED
AMERICA.
WHAT DO YOU THINK OF THAT?
WITH AMERICA.GOV, THE FEDERAL
GOVERNMENT NO LONGER STANDS IN
YOUR WAY.
IT STANDS FULLY AT YOUR SERVICE,
AND THAT IS WHAT WE ARE DOING.
SIMPLIFYING IT, GLAMORIZING IT,
MAKING WHAT IT SHOULD BE.
I WANT TO THINK THE MASTERMIND
BEHIND MANY OF THE INCREDIBLE
BREAKTHROUGHS WE HAVE JUST SEEN,
THE AIRBNB CO-FOUNDER, SMART
GUY, FRIEND OF MINE, CHIEF
DESIGN OFFICER OF THE UNITED
STATES OF AMERICA JOE GABIA.
THANK YOU, JOE.
GREAT JOB.
A VERY SPECIAL THANKS TO THE
CHIEF GRAND ARCHITECT OF THE
UNITED STATES, PETER ARNEAU.
I KNEW PETER IN THE OLD DAYS
WHEN HE WAS SLIGHTLY HEAVIER.
250 POUNDS.
NOBODY IS GOING TO BELIEVE THAT,
CHECK IT OUT.
AND I LIKE HIM BOTH WAYS.
[LAUGHTER]
IS DOCTOR LIKE SOME BETTER THIS
WAY.
A GREAT GUY, VERY INTELLIGENT
GUY.
THE LEAD ENGINEER ED CORISEEN.
IN THE ENTIRE TEAM AT THE
NATIONAL DESIGN STUDIO.
WE HAD A DESIGN STUDIO, DID NOT
EXIST AND NOW IS A BIG FACTOR IN
OUR COUNTRY.
GOING TO BE TALKING ABOUT IT,
HAVING TO DO WITH MANY OTHER
THINGS.
THESE INCREDIBLE PATRIOTS COULD
BE MAKING MILLIONS AND MILLIONS
OF DOLLARS -- ACTUALLY, THEY DID
, AND THEY DECIDED NOT TO MAKE
ANY MORE.
LET'S GO HERE, WE WANT TO BE
INVOLVED WITH THEIR GOVERNMENT
AND PUT OUR GOVERNMENT AHEAD.
THEY ARE WORKING 20-HOUR DAYS IN
GOVERNMENT ON BEHALF OF OUR
COUNTRY, AND WE SALUTE THEM.
THEY'RE THE MOST SUCCESSFUL
PEOPLE AT WHAT THEY DO, MAYBE
THE MOST, AND THEY GIVE IT ALL
UP TO COME HERE.
IT WAS A GOOD IDEA I HAD.
THEY ALL GAVE IT UP.
YOU GOT ME FOR NOTHING.
I DON'T TAKE MY SALARY.
DO YOU BELIEVE THAT?
NO OTHER PRESIDENT -- THEY THINK
THAT NO OTHER PRESIDENT HAS EVER
SERVED WITHOUT RECEIVING THEIR
SALARY.
THEY THINK GEORGE WASHINGTON,
WHO WAS ACTUALLY A VERY WEALTHY
MAN, THEY THINK GEORGE
WASHINGTON DID NOT GET A SALARY,
BUT THEY ARE NOT SURE ABOUT
THAT.
BUT THEY ARE SMART.
THEY TAKE THEIR SALARY.
I DECIDED NOT TO.
INCLUDING IN MY FIRST CHILD.
DO I GET THANKS FOR IT, NOT,
ZERO HERE NOBODY EVER SAYS, SIR.
OH, BOY.
BUT I ALSO HAVE TO THINK THE MEN
WHO INITIALLY ENVISIONED THE
TRANSFORMATION OF GOVERNMENT
THROUGH TECHNOLOGY AND PRODUCTS
THE TALENT TO GET THE -- A GREAT
GUY.
WE ARE PLEASED TO BE JOINED BY
MANY MEMBERS OF MY CABINET, THE
PRESIDENT OF META, DANNA POWELL,
MY FRIEND FOR A LONG TIME.
IS SHE HERE?
STAND UP.
[APPLAUSE]
OH.
HE MADE A GOOD MOVE.
I SAID, HOW DID HE THINK OF THAT
ONE?
THAT WAS A GOOD MOVE.
VERY SMART.
I HEARD THEY ARE DOING GREAT.
AN EXTRA LITTLE FLARE AND
SOMETHING SPECIAL WHEN THEY GO
WITH ME.
FOR A LONG TIME, SHE WAS WITH
ME.
PRETTY MUCH THE WHOLE TIME.
SHE SAW SOME INCREDIBLE THINGS
AND SO SOME NASTY PEOPLE.
WE MET A COUPLE NASTY ONCE, BUT
WE TOOK CARE OF THEM, DIDN'T WE?
SHE IS FANTASTIC.
AND COUNTLESS OTHER INNOVATORS,
TECHNOLOGY LEADERS AND PIONEERS
HERE THIS MORNING.
THIS ROOM IS AMAZING, ACTUALLY.
WE ARE LAUNCHING TODAY SOMETHING
THAT IS REALLY NOT SIMPLY
WEBSITE, IT IS A RESTORATION OF
AMERICA'S FOUNDING PROMISE, A
REINVENTION OF YOUR GOVERNMENT
FOR THE 21ST CENTURY AND BEYOND.
WE ARE PUTTING POWER AND CONTROL
BACK IN THE HANDS OF THE PEOPLE,
RIGHT WHERE IT BELONGS, 250
YEARS AGO, THE DECLARATION OF
INDEPENDENCE PROCLAIMED THAT
AMERICA'S GOVERNMENT EXISTS TO
SERVE AMERICAN CITIZENS.
YET, FOR TOO LONG, THE
EXPERIENCE OF OUR CITIZENS HAS
BEEN THE EXACT OPPOSITE.
WASHINGTON BUREAUCRACIES HAVE
GROWN EVER LARGER AND MORE
INTRUSIVE.
AND ARMIES OF FEDERAL
BUREAUCRATS HAVE BEHAVED AS IF
YOUR JOB IS TO ANSWER TO THEM,
NOT TO GOVERNMENT AND THE MUCH
MORE PRACTICAL AND SMALLER FORM.
THEY DID IT THE OTHER WAY
AROUND, AND THEY'RE NOT SUPPOSED
TO HAVE DONE THAT.
BUT ALL OF THAT CHANGE IS
STARTING RIGHT NOW.
GOVERNMENT HAS BEEN BROKEN FOR
MANY, MANY DECADES.
YOU COULD SAY PROBABLY CENTURIES
, WE DON'T GO BACK THAT LONG,
BUT THEY CAN'T BETWEEN NOW.
AND THE TRUMP ADMINISTRATION IS
FIXING IT.
WE ARE FIXING IT STARTING
IMMEDIATELY.
WE ACTUALLY STARTED THIS PROJECT
DURING DAY ONE.
[APPLAUSE]
THIS IS ACTUALLY VERY COMPLEX
PROJECT.
WE ACTUALLY STARTED THIS
TOLERANCE ON DAY ONE.
TO US THAT TIME TO GET THE VERY
COMPLEX SUBJECT MATTER MADE
SIMPLE.
AND IT IS MADE SIMPLE AND ALSO
MADE BEAUTIFUL.
WE ARE MAKING IT DRAMATICALLY
EASIER AND FASTER AND MORE
CONVENIENT TO GET WHAT YOU NEED,
EXACTLY WHEN YOU NEED IT.
AND FOR OUR ENTIRE LIVES, WE
HAVE BECOME USED TO A GOVERNMENT
SO BIG IT MAKES THE CITIZEN FEEL
VERY, VERY SMALL.
BUT WITH AMERICA.GOV, THE ENTIRE
U.S. GOVERNMENT WILL FIT IN THE
PLAN.
THINK OF THAT, WE HAVE A PLAN,
IT IS HELD IN THE PALM OF YOUR
HAND.
A VERY SIMPLE PLAN THAT SITS IN
THE PALM OF YOUR HANDS.
INSTEAD OF FORCING CITIZENS TO
SEARCH THROUGH THE ENDLESS MAZE
OF TENS OF THOUSANDS OF TERRIBLE
GOVERNMENT WEBSITES AND RULES
AND MORE THAT 10,000 FORMS TO DO
BASIC ACTS, YOU WILL NOW HAVE
ONE FRONT DOOR FOR EVERY SINGLE
QUESTION.
EVERYTHING WILL BE ANSWERED
EASILY AND QUICKLY.
A DIGITAL HOME BUILT AROUND YOUR
TI IN YOUR LIFE, YOU WILL SAVE
HOURS A HOURS, HUNDREDS OF
HOURS PERHAPS A YEAR, DEPENDING
ON HOW MUCH OF THAT TYPE OF
INFORMATION YOU NEED.
SIMPLY ASK FOR WHAT YOU NEED IN
AMERICA.GOV WILL PROVIDE ANSWERS
, AND IT WILL BE PROVIDED
IMMEDIATELY.
THINK OF THAT, IT IS AMAZING.
ANYONE WHO HAS USED GROK OR
GEMINI OR CHATGPT WILL
UNDERSTAND INSTANTLY HOW TO USE
AMERA.V.
NOT LICATED.
SECRETARY RUBIO, WHO IS DOING
A FANTASTIC JOB, DO A
PHENOMENAL JOB, WILL DEMONSTRATE
, GET A PASSPORT ONCE REQUIRED
APPOINTMENTS, PAPERWORK, AND
MONTHS OF WAITING.
NOW IT IS DONE IN A FEW SIMPLE
CLICKS.
VERY SPL
FOR YEARS, A WOMAN HE WANTED TO
CHANGE HER NAME AFTER GETTING
MARRIED AT TO NAVIGATE A
STRESSFUL BUREAUCRATIC PROCESS
THAT TOOK MONTHS AND MONTHS AND
EVEN
VERY SOON, ALL SHE WILL HAVE TO
DO IS ASK AMERICA.GOV AND IT
WILL FILL OUT THE FORMS, TRACK
THE PROGRESS AND SEND HER A NEW
SOCIAL SECURITY CARD, PASSPORT
AND INSURANCE CARD IN THE MAIL.
WHETHER YOU ARE A SCOUT LEADER
WHO WANTS TO RESERVE A CAMPSITE
AT A NATIONAL PARK, A SENIOR
CITIZEN TRYING TO CHOOSE A
MEDICARE PLAN, OR AN AMERICAN
VETERAN TRYING TO GET THE
BENEFITS YOU HAVE EARNED AND SO
JUSTLY DESERVE, AMERICA.GOV WILL
BE THERE TO HELP AND TO HELP YOU
ACCURATELY AND QUICKLY.
WITH THIS, NO ONE CAN NO LONGER
COMPLAIN ABOUT PROVIDING PROOF
OF CITIZENSHIP OR VOTER ID.
[APPLAUSE]
THEY ARE ALWAYS SAYING IT IS TOO
COMPLICATED.
IT IS NOT COMPLICATED ANYMORE.
TE
OTHER REASON BECAUSE THEY DON'T
WANT TO HAVE IT BE EASY, BUT IT
IS EASY BECAUSE YOU CAN GET
EVERYTHING NOW THAT YOU NEED IN
JUST ONE SIMPLE SWIPE.
SO, NOBODY WILL HAVE ANY EXCUSES
AND NOW CAN PASS IN THEORY VERY
EASILY THE SAVE AMERICA ACT
BECAUSE IT TAKES THE NUMBER ONE
EXCUSE AWAY FROM THEM.
AMERICANS CURRENTLY SPEND OVER
10 BILLION HOURS PER YEAR ON
GOVERNMENT PAPERWORK.
WE ARE GIVING THOSE 10 BILLION
HOURS BACK TO THE AMERICAN
PEOPLE.
ALL THAT TIME THEY SPEND.
UNDER THE TRUMP ADMINISTRATION,
WE BELIEVE YOUR TIME MATTERS AND
WE BELIEVE YOUR GOALS MATTER.
WE BELIEVE THE UNITED STATES OF
AMERICA SHOULD HAVE THE ULTIMATE
CITIZEN EXPERIENCE OF ANY
COUNTRY.
WE WILL EVEN BE BETTER THAN
SOME COUNTRIES THAT DO THIS IN
MUCH LESSER FORM.
WE WILL BE BETTER FOR MANY
COUNTRY, STARTING IMMEDIATELY.
AGAIN, THIS TOOK A WHILE TO
BRING IT TO A POINT WHERE IT IS
SO GOOD.
AMERICA.GOV IS A DECLARATION TO
THE WORLD THAT EVERY CITIZEN OF
OUR NATION WILL BE TREATED WITH
RESPECT AND DIGNITY.
THEY WILL NOT BE SHUT OUT BY
WORK THAT MAY BE DOES NOT EXIST
OR PAPERWORK THAT IS SO COMPLEX
THAT NOBODY CAN FIGURE OUT.
FOR DECADES, WASHINGTON HAS PAID
ENORMOUS SUMS OF TAXPAYER MONEY
TO FEDERAL CONTRACTORS TO BUILD
TERRIBLE WEBSITES THAT PALE IN
COMPARISON TO THE EXPERIENCE YOU
ARE USED TO IN THE PRIVATE
SECTOR.
AND SERIOUSLY COMPARED TO WHAT
WE HAVE BUILT.
THERE'S NOTHING LIKE IT.
WE HAVE SOME OF MY FRIENDS,
SERIOUS, HIGH TECH PEOPLE.
THEY LOOKED AT THIS AND CANNOT
BELIEVE IT.
THEY SAY THIS IS ONE OF THE MOST
INCREDIBLE THINGS THAT YOUR
GOVERNMENT HAS DONE.
I DON'T THINK SO, I THINK IT IS
DAMN GOOD.
SOMEONE SAID IT WILL BE THE
SINGLE BIGGEST THING YOU'VE DONE
IN GOVERNMENT.
I SAID I DON'T THINK SO BUT IT
IS DAMN GOOD.
JUST ANOTHER THING.
SIR, THERE'S NO QUESTION THIS
WILL BE THE BIGGEST THING.
IF IT IS THE BIGGEST THING I'VE
EVER DONE, I HAVE DONE A SHITTY
JOB AS PRESIDENT.
IT'S DAMN GOOD.
WITH AMERICA.GOV, FOR THE FIRST
TIME IN HISTORY, THE GOVERNMENT
IS OFFERING AN EXPERIENCE THAT
MATCHES AND IN SOME WAYS EVEN
EXCEEDS THE
STATE-OF-THE-ART.
IT IS BUILT WITH THE GROUND UP
WITH YOUR PRIVACY AND SECURITY
IN MIND.
THEY HAVE USED A BRAND-NEW
TECHNOLOGY, ABSOLUTELY
BRAND-NEW.
AMAZING.
PEOPLE DON'T EVEN HAVE ACCESS TO
IT FOR THE MOST PART.
TO ENSURE THAT YOUR PERSONAL
INFORMATION IS NOT COLLECTED OR
STORED, AND YOUR CONVERSATION
DISAPPEARS WHEN YOU LEAVE AND
EVERYTHING STAYS TOTALLY
PRIVATE.
CANNOT IN THEORY BE HACKED INTO
IT.
WHEN THEY FIGURE OUT A WAY TO DO
IT, WE WILL END IT BECAUSE THEY
ALWAYS FIGURE OUT.
WHEN YOU HAVE 197 IQ'S LOOKING
TO DO THINGS.
BUT WE CAN ALSO COUNTERACT THEM.
WE THINK IT MIGHT NOT HAPPEN
ACTUALLY.
THIS KIND OF INNOVATION IN
GOVERNMENT IS A PREVIEW OF
WHAT'S POSSIBLE WITH SUPER
INTELLIGENCE, OR SI, THE
OFFICIAL NAME IN THE UNITED
STATES.
I WILL BE SIGNING A VERY
POWERFUL EXECUTIVE ORDER.
I SPOKE TO PRESIDENT XI, HE
LOVES IT.
WHEN YOU SAY ARTIFICIAL -- THIS
IS EXTREME INTELLIGENCE.
IT IS SUPERIOR INTELLIGENCE.
IT'S SUPREME ALSO INTELLIGENCE.
THE WORD SUPER IS THE BEST WORD
OF ALL.
IT IS THE SIMPLEST.
WE WILL BE NAMING IT S.I., SUPER
INTELLIGENCE.
WE DON'T WANT TO HEAR
ARTIFICIAL.
IT IS NOT ARTIFICIAL.
IT IS VERY BRILLIANT, IT IS
POWERFUL.
BUT, WE ARE CHANGING THE NAME TO
SUPER INTELLIGENCE.
SO FAR -- EVERYBODY LIKES IT.
ARTIFICIAL INTELLIGENCE IS LIKE
THE NEWS, FAKE NEWS.
THE WORD ARTIFICIAL -- I COULD
CALL THEM ARTIFICIAL.
I THINK I FOUND A NEW NAME.
I'M GOING TO CALL THEM -- FORGET
ABOUT FAKE.
FAKE NEWS IS ONE OF MY GREAT
TERMS.
NOW, I WILL CALL THEM ARTIFICIAL
NEWS.
I LIKE THAT.
THE ARTIFICIAL NEWS THE
ARTIFICIAL NEWS.
LOOK AT ALL THOSE PRESS.
THERE ARE SOME BACK THERE THAT
ARE FABULOUS, LIKE TWO.
THIS IS ONE MORE EXAMPLE WHY I
WILL NEVER STIFLE THE GROWTH OF
TECHNOLOGY THAT WILL BE BIGGER
THAN THE INDUSTRIAL REVOLUTION.
S.I., SUPER INTELLIGENCE, THEY
ARE SAYING BIGGER THAN THE
INDUSTRIAL REVOLUTION.
FAR BIGGER THAN THE INTERNET.
AND WE SEE IT.
WE CANNOT STIFLE IT.
WE ARE LEADING BY A LOT.
PRESIDENT XI KNOWS THAT.
WE DON'T WANT TO MIX IT UP TOO
MUCH.
SOMEBODY SAID LET'S DO A JOINT
VENTURE, LET'S WORK TOGETHER
WITH CHINA.
IF WE DO THAT, WE WILL BE GIVING
A LOT OF SECRETS THAT WE HAVE
THAT THEY WOULD WANT TO HAVE OR
ANYBODY ELSE.
FRANKLY, THERE'S NOBODY IN THEIR
PLACE.
IT IS BETWEEN US AND CHINA.
PRESIDENT XI.
WAS HERE.
WE TALKED ABOUT IT.
WHY WOULD WE WANT TO DO
ANYTHING?
A LOT OF PEOPLE SAY LET'S DO IT
TOGETHER WITH CHINA, BUT THAT
THEY WOULD BE ABLE TO
IMMEDIATELY GAIN ACCESS TO
THINGS WE KNOW THEY DON'T KNOW.
WE DO WORK WITH THEM IN SO MANY
WAYS.
HOWEVER WHEN SUPER INTELLIGENCE
WINS.
IT IS AN EXPRESSION.
YOU HAVE A WINNER AND A LOSER.
YOU ARE PROBABLY NOT GOING TO
HAVE A SECOND PLACE.
HE WILL HAVE A WINNER OR A
LOSER.
WE ARE LEADING NOW OVER CHINA
AND EVERYONE ELSE.
I WANT TO KEEP IT THAT WAY.
THE ONLY WAY YOU CAN KEEP IT
THAT WAY IS TO DO EXACTLY WHAT
WE ARE DOING NOW.
WE DON'T WANT TO STIFLE GROWTH.
AT THE SAME TIME, WE WANT PEOPLE
TO BEHAVE HONESTLY.
WE WANT THEM TO BE TRUSTWORTHY.
THAT IS WHY WE HAVE THE DOJ,
THAT IS WHY WE HAVE THE FBI.
THAT IS WHY WE HAVE FORMS OF
GOVERNMENT THAT ARE VERY
EFFECTIVE IF PEOPLE DECIDE TO GO
DOWN A VERY DARK AND DANGEROUS
PATH.
AS JOE SAID, THE FIRST PART OF
AMERICA.GOV IS AVAILABLE TODAY,
BUT IT'S NOT THE END.
IT IS ONLY THE BEGINNING.
THIS IS AN INCREDIBLE THING FOR
OUR COUNTRY.
AS GREAT AS THE PRODUCT IS RIGHT
NOW AND IT WILL ONLY GET BETTER,
IT WILL EVOLVE AND GET BETTER IN
THE WEEKS AND MONTHS AHEAD.
I THINK VERY SUBSTANTIALLY, BY
LEAPS AND BOUNDS.
THAT IS WHY IN A MOMENT, I WILL
SIGN A HISTORIC EXECUTIVE ORDER
DIRECTING EVERY FEDERAL
GOVERNMENT AGENCY TO MAKE ALL OF
THEIR PUBLIC FACING SERVICES
INTEGRATE DIRECTLY WITH
AMERICA.GOV AS SOON AS POSSIBLE.
ALL OF THIS INTERFACE WILL GO
RIGHT INTO OUR GREAT, BRILLIANT
SUPER MIND.
A SUPER MIND.
THAT MIND WILL BE ABLE TO HANDLE
IT ALL VERY EASILY.
DISPENSE IT VERY EASILY.
OUR GOAL IS ANYTHING YOU MIGHT
NEED FROM THE UNITED STATES
GOVERNMENT WILL BE ACCESSIBLE AT
YOUR FINGERTIPS AND VERY QUICKLY
AT YOUR COMMAND.
ALL THIS IS A DAY -- YOU THINK
OF IT THIS WAY.
A LOT OF PEOPLE WILL.
THIS IS A DAY ALL AMERICANS WILL
BE EXTREMELY PROUD.
THIS IS A BIG THING.
THIS IS A VERY BIG THING, VERY
IMPORTANT THING.
GOING TO SAVE YOU A LOT OF TIME,
ACCURACY.
FROM MAKING A LOT OF MISTAKES AS
YOU DO.
IT IS NOT EVEN YOUR FAULT.
SO BAD, SO CUMBERSOME, SO
UNAVAILABLE THAT YOU ARE FORCED
TO MAKE MISTAKES AND
SOMETIMES YOU GET IN TROUBLE.
EVERY ADVANCED NATION IN THE
WORLD WILL COPY WHAT WE'VE DONE
HERE THIS MORNING, WE BELIEVE.
SOME WON'T BE ABLE TO BECAUSE
THEY DON'T HAVE THE TECHNOLOGY
TO DO IT.
THEY SHOULD TRY AND DO IT.
FOR YEARS, EVERYONE HAS
RECOGNIZED THE OLD SYSTEM OF BIG
GOVERNMENT BUREAUCRACY IS
FAILING AND OUTDATED.
WITH TODAY'S ORDER AND THE
LAUNCH OF AMERICA.GOV, THAT
SYSTEM IS FINALLY PASSING AWAY.
IT'S DEAD.
JUST LIKE TWO YEARS AGO, OUR
COUNTRY WAS DEAD AND NOW WE HAVE
THE HOTTEST COUNTRY ANYWHERE IN
THE WORLD.
IT WAS SAID TO ME BY NUMEROUS
LEADERS.
SIR, TWO YEARS AGO, YOUR COUNTRY
WAS DEAD.
NOW, YOU HAVE THE HOTTEST
COUNTRY ANYWHERE IN THE WORLD.
THAT'S EXACTLY TRUE.
AND IRAN WILL NOT HAVE A NUCLEAR
WEAPON AND THEY ARE FAILING VERY
BADLY.
IT WILL BE OVER WITH VERY SOON.
THEY WILL NOT HAVE A NUCLEAR
WEAPON.
THE OIL PRICES WILL BE TUMBLING
DOWN JUST LIKE THEY WERE BEFORE
I HAD TO MAKE THAT LITTLE
EXCURSION TO THE ISLAMIC
REPUBLIC OF IRAN.
I THINK IN THE YEARS TO COME,
THEY WILL BE WRITING BOOKS,
WRITING THE HISTORY OF OUR
COUNTRY AND SAY THAT IS ONE OF
THE MOST IMPORTANT THINGS WE
DID.
THAT IS ACTUALLY ONE OF THE MOST
IMPORTANT THINGS WE HAVE DONE.
UNDER MY ADMINISTRATION, WE'RE
RENEWING THE SACRED BOND OF
TRUST BETWEEN THE PEOPLE AND
THEIR GOVERNMENT FOR OUR 250TH
YEAR.
IN EVERYTHING WE DO, WE ARE
REASSERTING AMERICA'S IDENTITY
AS A NATION THAT WORKS, A NATION
THAT BUILDS, A NATION THAT
SOLVES PROBLEMS, SEIZES
OPPORTUNITIES AND USES THE NEXT
GREAT INVENTIONS TO FIX WHAT IS
BROKEN.
THERE HAS BEEN A LOT THAT HAS
BEEN BROKEN.
WE DON'T ACCEPT MEDIOCRITY OR
STAGNATION ESPECIALLY IN
GOVERNMENT BECAUSE AMERICANS
BELIEVE IN EXCELLENCE AND
CONSTANT IMPROVEMENT.
IF WE DON'T IMPROVE, EVERYONE
WILL CATCH US.
WE DO NOT SURRENDER TO FEARS
ABOUT WHAT TECHNOLOGIES WILL DO
TO US.
WE DECIDE THOSE TECHNOLOGIES
WILL DO FOR US AND VERY
INCREDIBLE THINGS, ESPECIALLY IN
THE FIELD OF MEDICAL.
SOME OF THE THINGS THAT ARE
COMING UP MEDICALLY, PEOPLE
THOUGHT WOULD NEVER HAPPEN AND
NOW THEY ARE HAPPENING IN A
MATTER OF WEEKS.
THINGS ARE HAPPENING IN THE
MEDICAL WORLD THAT ARE
INCREDIBLE.
WE NEVER RETREAT FROM A
FRONTIER.
WE NEVER SHRINK FROM A CHALLENGE
.
WE PUSH FORWARD AND BUILD A
WORLD THAT IS BIGGER, BETTER,
FASTER, SMARTER THAN IT'S EVER
BEEN BEFORE.
TODAY, JUST AS OUR FOUNDERS DID
2.5 CENTURIES AGO, WE CARRY OUR
FLAG ACROSS THE NEXT HORIZON AND
PROUDLY DECLARE WE ARE AMERICANS
AND THE FUTURE BELONGS TO US.
I JUST WANT TO THANK YOU.
GOD BLESS YOU ALL AND I WILL NOW
SOUND THE EXECUTIVE ORDER --
SIGN THE EXECUTIVE ORDER.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH, EVERYBODY.
[APPLAUSE]
♪
PRES. TRUMP: I THINK THE CABINET
WILL BE COMING UP.
THANK YOU.
READY?
[APPLAUSE]
♪
>> TAKING A BREAK IN THIS
PROGRAM HOSTED BY THE TRUMP
ADMINISTRATION AS THEY UNVEIL
AMERICA.GOV, A NEW AI POWERED
SITE TO PROVIDE ACCESS TO
GOVERNMENT INFORMATION AND
SERVICES.
WHEN IT RESUMES, WE WILL BRING
YOU MORE LIVE COVERAGE ON
CSPAN3.
>> THIS WILL TRULY BE AN AMAZING
DAY.
WE GATHERED IN THIS AUDITORIUM
SOME OF THE GREATEST LEADERS,
BUILDERS, INNOVATORS AND
CITIZENS OF THIS COUNTRY.
TODAY, WE WILL SEE THIS VISION
TURNED INTO REALITY.
ONE THAT WILL CHANGE HOW THE
GOVERNMENT RECOGNIZES YOU,
RESPECT YOUR TIME AND HOW IT
SERVES YOU.
I REALLY BELIEVE THIS IS A
HISTORY MAKING EVENT.
I SPENT ALMOST MY ENTIRE ADULT
LIFE DEDICATED TO A PEOPLE TO
FIND WAYS TO SIGNIFICANTLY
INCREASE THEIR LIVES.
OUR GOVERNMENT SOMETIMES TURNS
INTO A GIANT
BUREAUCRACY.
AND HE WENT TO HAVE EVER BEEN TO
THE DMV KNOWS WHAT I AM TALKING
ABOUT.
IT IS ABSURD.
>> WORKING TIRELESSLY TO IMPROVE
THE HEALTH OF AMERICANS.
HE'S RESPONSIBLE FOR MEDICARE,
MEDICAID.
165 MILLION AMERICANS EVERY DAY.
DR. MEHMET OZ.
[APPLAUSE]
DR. OZ: HELLO, AMERICA.
THAT'S THE MESSAGE TODAY.
JOE HAS DONE A FANTASTIC JOB.
JOE AND I HAVE BEEN THROUGH THIS
ONCE BEFORE.
MANY OF YOU HAVE HEARD THE
PROJECT, IT IS CALLED TRUMP RX.
IT LAID THE GROUNDWORK OR HOW WE
WORK ACROSS AGENCIES AND IT HAS
WORKED UNBELIEVABLE.
SOMETHING YOU WOULD EXPECT FROM
SOMEONE WHO BUILT A MASSIVE
BUSINESS.
THAT IS THE PRESIDENT'S BIG
MESSAGE, HE IS IN THE
HOSPITALITY SPACE.
HE WANTS TO HOLD THE EVENT FOR
THE AMERICAN PEOPLE TO TALK TO
US SO WE CAN TALK BACK.
HERE'S WHAT HAPPENED WITH
TRUMPRX.GOV.
PRESCRIPTION DRUG PRICES STARTED
WITH HIGH GROWTH.
PRICES ARE NOT FALLING AT THE
FASTEST RATE THIS YEAR
MORE THAN IT HAS IN 60 YEARS.
NO ONE THOUGHT THAT WAS
POSSIBLE.
WITH THE PATIENT SEIZES
INCREDIBLY SIMPLE WHICH IS WHY
ITORKS.
I HAVE GOT MY CLICKER, GUYS.
THE ONE THING I NEEDED.
THIS IS WHAT YOU DO, YOU GO ON
THE SITE, THE PRESCRIPTIONS ARE
ALL THERE.
YOU ACTUALLY GET THE FORM THAT
YOU WANT, WHAT STRENGTH, HOW
MANY YOU WANT.
THIS IS THE PART I REALLY LIKE.
ONCE YOU HAVE DONE THAT, ALL YOU
NEED TO DO IS GET A COUPON AND
YOU ARE OFF TO THE RACES.
IT MAKES SOMETHING
SUPER SIMPLE THAT USED
TO BE ENORMOUSLY COMPLEX.
BEHIND THIS, THERE IS STILL THAT
COMPLEXITY.
HERE'S WHAT REALLY HAPPENED IN
ORDER TO DO THIS.
TO CREATE TRUMP RX, WE HAD TO DO
A LOT OF NEGOTIATIONS WITH DRUG
COMPANIES.
WE HAD TO WORK WITH PHARMACIES
AND PHARMACISTS.
ALL OF THAT HAPPENED BECAUSE WE
HAD UNBELIEVABLE HIGH QUALITY
PEOPLE COMING INTO GOVERNMENT TO
SERVE THIS ADMINISTRATION SO WE
CAN ENSURE WE GO HEAD TO HEAD
WITH SOME OF THE BIGGEST
COMPANIES IN THE WORLD.
THE VALUE OF THIS -- $650
BILLION OVER 10 YEARS.
THAT IS IN THE POCKETS OF
AMERICANS WHO CAN AFFORD TO TAKE
ON THEIR MEDICATIONS.
ONE IN THREE PEOPLE GO TO A
DRUGSTORE AND LEAVE BECAUSE THEY
CANNOT AFFORD THEM.
THEY CAN GO FORWARD AND LIVE
THEIR LIVES COMFORTABLY AND DO
ALL THE THINGS THEY WANT TO DO.
IT DOES NOT HURT THEM.
IT WORKS FOR THEM IN THEIR TIME
OF NEED.
TRUMPRX WORKS SO WELL, WE WILL
TAKE THAT SAME APPROACH TO
MEDICARE.
THAT IS A BIG ANNOUNCEMENT
TODAY.
MY FRIENDS, WE NEED TO TALK.
I CANNOT HELP YOU IF I CAN'T
TALK TO YOU.
I'M A DOCTOR.
YOU CANNOT START BY JUST DOING
THINGS.
WE TALK TO PEOPLE.
WE ARE MAKING TALKING TO YOU
REALLY HARD NOW.
IT STARTS WITH A VERY SIMPLE
STEP.
IF YOU WANT TO SIGN UP FOR
MEDICARE, YOU SHOULD CLICK A
BUTTON AND SIGN UP FOR MEDICARE.
FOR MOST AMERICANS, THAT STARTS
AT 65.
IT TURNS OUT TO BE A LOT MORE
COMPLICATED.
IT DEPENDS ON WHERE YOU ARE IN
YOUR LIFE.
ARE YOU STILL WORKING?
THERE ARE A LOT MORE QUESTIONS
YOU CAN PUT UP.
IS YOUR SPOUSE STILL WORKING?
DO YOU HAVE OTHER INSURANCE?
ALL THOSE ANSWERS AND OTHERS
INFORM WHETHER YOU SHOULD SIGN
UP FOR MEDICARE AND WHAT KIND.
THESE PROGRAM SUPPORTS 70
MILLION AMERICANS.
OVERALL, THE AGENCY'S HUNDRED 65
MILLION PEOPLE.
TODAY, ONE OF THE WAYS WE WILL
HELP YOU IS TO GIVE YOU A BOOK.
THIS BOOK COSTS US $100 MILLION
A YEAR TO PRINT AND SHIP TO THE
AMERICAN PEOPLE.
HAS ANYONE READ THIS BOOK?
NEVER ONCE.
NO ONE SHOULD.
WE SHOULD NOT MAKE MEDICARE
EASIER TO STUDY BY SENDING YOU A
BOOK.
WE SHOULD MAKE IT EASIER TO USE.
THAT IS THE GOAL TODAY.
THAT IS WHY HEALTH AND HUMAN
SERVICES AND SECRETARY KENNEDY,
WHO HAS SIGNED ON TO THIS, IS
PROUD TO BE A FOUNDING AGENCY
PARTNER WITH AMERICA.GOV.
LET ME SHOW YOU WHAT THIS
INTELLIGENT NEW EXPERIENCE WITH
OUR GOVERNMENT, YOUR GOVERNMENT
ACTUALLY LOOKS LIKE.
LISA IS AN INTERESTING WOMAN.
HER HUSBAND JIM.
SHE IS OVER 65.
SHE IS STILL WORKING.
HER INSURANCE COME THROUGH HER
JOB BUT SHE IS TRYING TO SLOW
DOWN.
SHE WILL HAVE TO FIGURE OUT WHAT
TO DO.
SHE'S NEVER REALLY UNDERSTOOD
HOW TO SIGN UP FOR MEDICARE.
LISA IS HERE.
GIVE ME A LITTLE MOTION.
HOW WAS IT SIGNING UP FOR
MEDICARE?
>> HORRIBLE.
DR. OZ: THANK YOU FOR BEING
KIND.
I GET ALL THE COMPLAINTS FOR
LET'S SEE WHAT HAPPENS WHEN LISA
ASKS HER GOVERNMENT A SIMPLE
QUESTION.
CAN YOU HELP ME SIGN UP?
SHE WRITES THE QUESTION I AM 66
YEARS OF AGE.
WHY?
BECAUSE AT 65, SHE TRIED TO SIGN
UP AND WAS NOT ABLE TO.
SHE LITERALLY GET GAVE UP
SIGNING UP FOR FREE HEALTH CARE
THROUGH MEDICARE.GOV OR THE
VERSION SHE WAS ELIGIBLE FOR
BECAUSE SHE COULD NOT FIGURE IT
OUT.
WE WILL MOVE FROM -- INTO AN
ACTION.
NOT JUST A QUESTION.
THIS IS A SECURE SITE.
WE HAVE ALL THE QUESTIONS
PROTECTED, WE DON'T TRACK WHAT
YOU DO AFTERWARDS.
WE WANT TO MOVE INTO ACTUAL
DOING THINGS.
AMERICA.GOV DO SOMETHING REALLY
IMPORTANT.
YOU SECURELY CONNECT LISA TO THE
SYSTEM WITH A LOGIN.
THIS IS LIKE WHEN YOU GO TO THE
AIRPORT.
SAME CONCEPT.
WE KNOW WHO YOU ARE.
NOW THAT I KNOW WHO YOU ARE, WE
CAN TALK.
YOU OWN YOUR INFORMATION.
YOU CAN IDENTIFY WHO SHE IS.
WHO SHE IS, ALL OF THAT IS ON
THE PLATFORM.
HERE SHE HAS ALL THE DIFFERENT
GROUPS SHE WANTS TO WORK WITH.
THIS IS IMPORTANT BECAUSE SHE
CAN TELL ME SHE CAN TELL ME SHE
WANTS TO TALK TO SOCIAL SECURITY
OR VETERAN AFFAIRS.
THIS IS AN INTERESTING POINT.
WHY DID SHE HAVE TO TALK TO
VETERAN AFFAIRS?
IN THEORY, I SHOULD BE ABLE TO
TALK TO SOCIAL SECURITY
ADMINISTRATOR.
IS FRANK IN THE HOUSE?
HE ACTUALLY RUN SOCIAL SECURITY.
I CAN CALL HIM ON THE PHONE BUT
YOU CAN'T.
IF I KNOW WHAT YOU NEED TO DO, I
CAN DIGITALLY TELL SOCIAL
SECURITY, LET ME KNOW IF LISA IS
ELIGIBLE.
LISA SIGNED INTO AMERICA.GOV AND
WITH HER PERMISSION, WE WE CAN
TRULY RETRIEVE INFORMATION THAT
WE ALREADY KNOW ABOUT HER.
THERE'S ALREADY STUFF OUT THERE
THAT WE KNOW.
WE MIGHT AS WELL SHARE IT WITH
YOU SO YOU CAN JUDGE IF IT IS
CORRECT.
YOU CAN GET IT FROM AGENCIES.
LISA, HER NAME, DATE OF BIRTH.
THAT IS WHAT WE USE TO DECIDE
THE BENEFITS.
LISA DOES NOT HAVE TO FIND IT.
SHE DOES NOT HAVE TO REENTER IT.
SHE DOESN'T HAVE TO CARRY FROM
ONE AGENCY TO ANOTHER.
WE DO THAT FOR HER.
THIS GOVERNMENT IS NOW WORKING
WITH LISA, TOGETHER WITH LISA,
NOT AROUND LISA.
THAT IS THE ELEGANCE OF
AMERICA.GOV.
WHEN I CALL COMMISSIONER FRANK,
ANSWERS THE CALL.
THAT IS THE ELEGANCE OF WHAT WE
NEED TO DO MOVING FORWARD.
SO, WE GET ALL THIS INFORMATION.
NOW WE HAVE TO ASK A SIMPLE
QUESTION.
WE HAD ALL THE DATA, THE
DEMOGRAPHIC SO WE KNOW ALL THE
HISTORY.
THE INTELLIGENCE OF AMERICA.GOV.
SHE'S GONE THROUGH WITH US
BASICALLY ALL THE QUESTIONS WE
HAD EARLIER BUT WE TOLD HER WHAT
SHE NEEDS TO NOTE.
INSTEAD OF WORKING THROUGH THE
QUESTION, WE CAN FOCUS HER
ATTENTION ON THE QUESTIONS THAT
MATTER.
FOR EXAMPLE, IS SHE STILL
WORKING?
WILL SHE KEEP OR LOSE HER
INSURANCE?
IF SHE LOSES THE INSURANCE, SHE
CHECKS THE BOX AND THEN THAT
AFFECTS WHEN AND HOW SHE ROLLS
IN MEDICARE.
IT IS A SIMPLE QUESTION AND
ANSWER.
IT EXPLAINS WHAT APPLIES TO
LISA'S SITUATION AND GUIDES OR
THROUGH DECISIONS.
FOR EXAMPLE, MEDICARE PART A OR
PART B.
YOU DON'T HAVE TO KNOW THAT.
SHE DOES NOT EVEN KNOW THAT.
THE DIFFERENCE IS IRRELEVANT TO
YOU BUT IT MATTERS TO US, SO
AMERICA.GOV WILL DO IT FOR YOU.
WHEN SHE'S READY, SHE REVIEWS
IT, LISA SUBMITS IT LISA IS
DONE.
HER APPLICATION GOES TO SOCIAL
SECURITY FOR REVIEW AND THEN
THERE YOU HAVE IT.
LISA'S RELATIONSHIP WITH
MEDICARE DOES NOT STOP.
NOW, SHE GETS TO USE IT.
THIS IS THE PART THAT WILL BLOW
YOUR MIND.
THIS IS WHAT WE ARE WORKING ON.
IN 2027, ALL OF THIS WILL BE
ELIGIBLE FOR YOU TO USE
COMFORTABLY.
AMERICA.GOV INTELLIGENTLY
SERVICES THE NEXT STEP FOR HER,
WHICH IS FOR MOST PEOPLE, GET ME
ACCESS.
IS THAT OF SENDING LISA OFF TO
SEARCH FOR ONE HERSELF,
AMERICA.GOV SHOWS HER NEARBY
PROVIDERS WHO ACCEPT MEDICARE.
LOOK AT THESE WONDERFUL DOCTORS.
SHE JUST FIXED THE ONE SHE
WANTS.
THE ONE THAT WORKS WITH HER
BECAUSE THEY ARE IN HER
INSURANCE.
WE WILL SHOW HER AVAILABLE
APPOINTMENT TIMES.
NO SEARCH, NO PHONE CALL, NO
WAITING ON HOLD.
DOES THAT SOUND PRETTY GOOD?
[APPLAUSE]
WE HEAR ABOUT THESE ALL THE
TIME.
WE ARE TALKING ABOUT MAKING
DAY-TO-DAY LIFE FOR AMERICANS.
FIXING THE POTHOLES THAT YOU GET
DAY IN AND DAY OUT SO YOU DON'T
HAVE TO WORRY ABOUT IT ANYMORE.
ONCE LISA TAKES THE TIME THAT
WORKS FOR HER, AMERICA.GOV BOOKS
THE APPOINTMENT.
ALL BECAUSE LISA'S CARE DOES NOT
HAVE TO STOP BECAUSE YOU CANNOT
FIGURE THIS SYSTEM OUT.
THERE IS MORE.
WE HAVE SO MUCH WE CAN DO.
THOSE 29,000 WEBSITES WE HAVE IN
THE FEDERAL GOVERNMENT AND
MAKING IT ACCESSIBLE.
AMERICA.GOV CAN UNDERSTAND
HER PRESCRIPTION COVERAGE.
THEY CAN LOOK AT MEDICARE PART D
AND COMPARE THE PLANS BASED ON
THE MEDICINE SHE TAKES.
SHE'S ON THESE TWO MEDICATIONS
AND SHE DOES NOT HAVE TO EXPLAIN
WHY.
WE KNOW SHE'S ON THESE.
DOES NOT MISSPELL THE
MEDICATIONS.
AMERICA.GOV ALREADY KNOWS SHE'S
USING THESE PRODUCTS.
THESE ARE MEDICATIONS WIDELY
USED.
NOTHING FANCY HERE.
ONCE WE KNOW WHERE SHE WANTS TO
AND THERE ARE A LOT OF THEM.
WHY WOULD WE CONFUSE YOU?
WHY WILL YOU MAKE YOU CUT CASES
INTO ANOTHER FRONTIER?
IT'S RIGHT HERE.
THE QUALITY OF THE PROGRAMS.
THE MONTHLY PREMIUM.
THE YEARLY DEDUCTIBLE.
WHAT ARE LISA'S PRESCRIPTIONS
COSTING HER OUT OF POCKET?
ALL SIDE-BY-SIDE AS YOU CAN SEE.
YOU SEE WHERE ONE CAN COST
BEFORE AND ANOTHER MIGHT SAVE
HER MONEY.
AND WHAT SHE IS GETTING FOR THE
DIFFERENCE.
THAT IS THE GAME.
THAT IS THE TRANSPARENCY YOU
WANT.
WE GIVE THE TRANSPARENCY THAT
YOU CAN GET THE BEST VALUE FOR
YOUR MONEY.
AMERICA.GOV MAKES IT CLEAR.
EVERYTHING LISA HAS DONE HAS
SAVED HER ON THE HER AMERICA.GOV
DASHBOARD.
IF LIFE GETS IN THE WAY, SHE CAN
LEAVE AND SHE DOESN'T LOSE THIS
INFORMATION.
THE PART D PLAN, YOU KNOW.
YOU KNOW THE WELLNESS VISIT.
ALL THE THINGS THAT ARE
IMPORTANT.
EXACTLY WHERE SHE LEFT OFF.
YOU CAN SEE WHAT IS COMPLETE AND
WHAT IS PENDING AND WHAT COMES
NEXT.
THAT IS IMPORTANT.
WHEN YOU HAVE WATCHED THE
CONVERSATION, MAYBE FOR THE
FIRST TIME, BETWEEN OUR
GOVERNMENTS AND THE WEBSITE,
AMERICA.GOV, LISA ASKED THE
QUESTION, HER GOVERNMENT
UNDERSTOOD HER SITUATION.
BECAUSE OF THAT, IT BROUGHT ALL
THE INFORMATION SHE NEEDS
TOGETHER.
SHE CAN ENROLL, FIND DOCTORS,
FIND MEDICINE.
ONE EXPERIENCE.
IT WILL GO FROM ANSWER TO ACTION
WITHOUT LEAVING THE EXPERIENCE.
I HAVE A SURPRISE FOR YOU.
WITH HIS ADMINISTRATION WOULD
LIKE TO DO THINGS.
AS YOU CAN ENROLL LISA RIGHT
NOW.
SHE HAS BEEN STRUGGLING FOR A
YEAR.
THE POPULAR ACCLAIM.
AND I WILL ASK [ INDISCERNIBLE ]
TO COME OUT.
THANK YOU, LISA.
THE KEY QUESTION WE ARE ASKING,
CAN YOU SIGN ME UP?
GIVE US A LITTLE BIT OF WHAT IT
WAS LIKE LAST YEAR AND HOW DO
YOU FEEL ABOUT THIS?
>> YOU HAVE UNDERSOLD THE PAIN.
PART A, B, C.
THERE IS A WINDOW AND A PENALTY
AND A GAP.
FIND YOUR DOCTOR.
I AM INTACT.
I KICK THE CAN DOWN THE ROAD.
YOU ARE CORRECT.
I DIDN'T DO IT.
>> WHAT DOES IT FEEL LIKE TODAY
TO THINK, MAYBE BECAUSE OF THIS,
IT WOULD BE IF YOU CLICKS?
>> IT WOULD BE AMAZING.
>> GOOD ENOUGH TO DO IT NOW?
>> YES.
>> WE DID IT FOR YOU.
>> THIS IS WHAT EVERY MEDICARE
BENEFICIARY GETS.
I GOT ONE OF THESE LAST YEAR.
>> IT IS A CLUB I JOINED LAST
YEAR.
EVERY BENEFICIARY GETS THIS.
>> WHAT ARE YOU GOING TO DO WITH
THAT?
>> I HAVE TO FIGURE OUT HOW TO
GET IT HOME.
>> ALL RIGHT.
>> LIKE TO SAY THANK YOU.
THANK YOU TO PRESIDENT TRUMP AND
ALL THE PEOPLE THAT WORKED ON
THIS.
LIKE I SAID, I'M IN TECH.
THIS IS TECHNOLOGY AND DEPLOYING
IT FOR AMERICAN PEOPLE AND
PROGRAMS.
IT IS EASY FOR US TO DO IT WHEN
WE NEEDED.
THAT IS AMAZING.
DR. OZ.
MAKES ME PROUD.
THE NIXON ADMINISTRATION.
IT HAS B A LONG TIME.
HAVING THE DESIGNED TO COME IN
AND HELP PEOPLE AND UNDERSTAND
HOW TO NAVIGATE.
>> THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
DR. OZ: HELPING AMERICANS LIVE
THEIR LIVES WITHOUT HAVING TO
GET INVOLVED.
IT IS A PROMISE BY A GOVERNMENT
TALKING TO YOU AND IS HEARING
YOU.
A GOVERNMENT THAT UNDERSTANDS
WHAT YOU NEED.
A GOVERNMENT THAT SAYS THEY ARE
THERE FOR YOU AND THEY WILL STAY
TH YOU UNTIL THE JOB IS DONE.
THAT IS OUR PROMISE TO YOU.
THAT IS WHAT THE PRESIDENT HAS
INSISTED ON SINCE DAY ONE.
MAKE LIFE EASIER.
THAT COMES IN MANY FORMS.
THIS IS A PARTICULARLY VALUABLE
ONE.
MEDICARE BEING AN IMPORTANT
EXAMPLE ACROSS THE BOARD FOR
165 MILLION AMERICANS LIKE IT
MEDICARE AND MEDICAID AND OBAMA
CARE.
WE WANT THE SYSTEMS TO INTEGRATE
AND HELP AMERICANS DO THE RIGHT
THING.
IT IS MOST VALUABLE RESOURCE WE
HAVE.
EACH OTHER.
THE AMERICAN PEOPLE.
LET ME SHOW YOU ANOTHER
ESSENTIAL GOVERNMENT SERVICE.
THIS IS PRETTY IMPORTANT.
IT HAS BEEN REIMAGINED AROUND
THE WAY AMERICA SERVES.
THE WAY AMERICA WANTS TO LIVE
ITS LIFE.
IT IS CALLED, THE UNITED STATES
PASSPORT.
TO SHOW YOU THAT, PLEASE WELCOME
MY GOOD FRIEND, A BIG UNIVERSITY
OF FLORIDA FAN.
BECAUSE OF HIS SON IN PART, THE
SECRETARY OF STATE OF THE UNITED
STATES, MARCO RUBIO.
[APPLAUSE].
>> HIS SON IS PLAYING FOR THE
UNIVERSITY OF FLORIDA.
HE WENT THERE TOO.
YOU STILL CELEBRATING.
>> THEY DON'T GIVE YOU COULD
TROPHIES FOR 4-0.
WE HAVE TO KEEP PLAYING.
GO GATORS.
ALL RIGHT, GOOD.
THAT WAS ACTUALLY PRETTY
AMAZING.
REMARKABLE.
THIS IS REALLY GOING TO BE A
REVOLUTION IN A WAY THAT
GOVERNMENT WORKS FOR THE AVERAGE
AMERICAN.
JUST THINK ABOUT IT FOR A MOMENT
WHAT YOU JUST SAW.
THEY TOOK SOMETHING THAT
MILLIONS OF AMERICANS DEAL WITH
EVERY SINGLE DAY AND THEY MADE
IT SIMPLER AND THEY MADE IT
EASIER AND THEY MADE IT MORE
EFFECTIVE AND THEY MADE IT THAT
WAY IN EVERY POSSIBLE WAY.
THAT IS JUST ONE PIECE OF WHAT
WE ARE HERE TO TALK ABOUT TODAY.
EARLIER THIS YEAR, JOE CAME TO
MY OFFICE AND HE SHOWED ME
AMERICA.GOV.
IT IS A WHOLE OF GOVERNMENT
PROJECT AND IT TOUCHES ON EVERY
DEPARTMENT AND EVERY AGENCY AND
EVERY BOROUGH YOU CAN IMAGINE.
AND IN EACH AND EVERY CASE, THE
GOAL IS SIMPLE.
TO MAKE LIFE BETTER AND EASIER
FOR NORMAL AMERICANS.
YOU HEARD A FEW EXAMPLES
ALREADY.
FOR US AT THE STATE DEPARTMENT,
ONE PARTICULAR THING CAME TO
MIND.
THE PASSPORT.
TODAY, MORE THAN HALF OF
AMERICANS HAVE THEM.
AND IT HAS COME A LONG WAY SINCE
THE EARLY DAYS OF THIS COUNTRY.
LET ME SHOW YOU.
THIS IS WHAT IT LOOKED LIKE IN
1781.
JUST A PIECE OF PAPER.
A VERY NICE ONE.
AND IN TIME, THAT PIECE OF PAPER
BECAME A BOOKLET.
THAT BOOKLET THEN INTRODUCED A
PHOTOGRAPH.
AND THEN WE INTO THE COMPUTER
AGE OF ELECTRONIC CHIPS.
FROM THE WAX SEAL TO THE
ELECTRONIC CHIP, THE AMERICAN
PASSPORT HAS BECOME THE MOST
TRUSTED AND POWERFUL AND I WOULD
ARGUE MOST IMPORTANT IDENTITY
DOCUMENT IN THE ENTIRE WORLD.
THE DOCUMENT KEPT EVOLVING.
AND THE PROCESS OF GETTING WANT
TO NOT CONTINUE TO INVOLVE.
TODAY, IF YOU NEED YOUR FIRST
PASSPORT, YOU STARTED THE STATE
DEPARTMENT WEBSITE.
THIS IS WHAT GREETS YOU.
NOT BAD.
A LOT OF INFORMATION.
IF YOU WANT TO APPLY, THAT IS
WHERE THIS STARTS.
YOU HAVE TO KNOW WHICH FORM TO
PRINT.
YOU HAVE TO SCHEDULE AN
APPOINTMENT AND YOU HAVE TO WAIT
IN LINE AND WHEN SOMETHING IS
THIS HARD, SOMEONE IS BOUND TO
MAKE MONEY OFF OF IT.
SO TODAY, THERE IS AN ENTIRE
INDUSTRY BUILT AROUND CACHING
AND AROUND EVERY STAGE OF THE
PASSPORT PROCESS.
SOME OF THESE SITES ARE CHARGING
YOU FOR FORMS THAT ARE FREE.
SOME ARE CHARGING YOU FOR
APPOINTMENTS THAT ARE FREE.
AFTER THEY TAKE YOUR MONEY, THEY
TAKE YOUR MOST SENSITIVE
INFORMATION TOO.
AND IF YOU MAKE IT THROUGH ALL
OF THE, SOMETIME IN THE FUTURE,
YOU GET THIS IN THE MAIL.
THIS IS WHAT ARRIVES.
THAT IS NOT REALLY THE KIND OF
PACKAGING YOU WOULD EXPECT FOR
THE MOST POWERFUL IDENTITY
DOCUMENT YOU WILL EVER RECEIVE.
WE SHIP TENS OF MILLIONS OF
THESE ENVELOPES EVERY YEAR.
THE UNITED STATES PASSPORT MEANS
SOMETHING.
IS A PHYSICAL SYMBOL OF WHO WE
ARE.
IT IS A PROMISE THAT WHEREVER
YOU GO IN THE WORLD AS AN
AMERICAN, YOU ARE ONE OF US.
I THINK YOU WOULD AGREE THAT
AMERICAN CITIZENS DESERVE BETTER
THAN THIS.
AND THAT IS WHY THE STATE
DEPARTMENT HAS PARTNERED WITH
AMERICA.GOV TO REBUILD THE
ENTIRE THING FROM THE GROUND UP
AND IT BEGINS WITH SOMETHING YOU
REMARKABLE.
STARTING NEXT YEAR, AMERICANS
WILL BE ABLE TO APPLY FOR THE
FIRST PASSPORT ENTIRELY ONLINE.
[CHEERING] [APPLAUSE].
>> LET ME SHOW YOU HOW EASY IT
IS.
YOU WOULD ASK, HOW DO I APPLY
FOR MY FIRST PASSPORT?
WHEN I'M SIGNED IN WITH
LOGIN.GOV, I CAN SECURELY SEE
THE INFORMATION THAT THE
GOVERNMENT ALREADY HAS ABOUT ME
IN THE SYSTEM.
I DON'T HAVE TO TYPE THE SAME
THING OVER AND OVER AND OVER
AGAIN.
NOW THE FUN PART.
THE PHOTO.
YOU CAN TAKE A NEW ONE YOURSELF
ON THE PHONE.
YOU PROBABLY CAN'T USE THE
FILTERS TO MAKE YOU LOOK 50
YEARS YOUNGER BUT YOU CAN TAKE A
PICTURE OF YOURSELF ON THE PHONE
IN THE COMFORT OF YOUR OWN HOME
OR YOU CAN UPLOAD ONE DIRECTLY
FROM YOUR OWN DEVICE.
YOU ARE NOT GOING ANY LONGER TO
THE DRUGSTORE TO GET YOUR
PICTURE TAKEN BEHIND A WHITE
SCREEN.
AND YOU CAN SEE YOUR PHOTO IN
THE CONTEXT OF THE FINISHED
PASSPORT.
AND IF YOU DON'T LIKE IT, AND AS
YOU KNOW, MANY PEOPLE DON'T LIKE
IT.
WE HAVE TO TAKE 150 OF THESE.
EVENTUALLY YOU WILL LIKE ONE AND
YOU CAN RETAKE IT UNTIL IT IS A
PERFECT SHOT OF THE ONE YOU
LIKE.
I HAVE TO SAY THIS.
THIS MIGHT BE THE MOST BEAUTIFUL
GOVERNMENT CHECK OUT I HAVE EVER
SEEN.
I'M SECURELY LOGGED INTO
LOGIN.GOV.
MY NAME AND ADDRESS ARE HERE.
I ENTER MY PAYMENT SECURELY.
LET'S CHECK OUT.
AND THAT'S IT.
YOUR PAYMENT IS COMPLETE.
MY FIRST APPLICATION.
NO PRINTING FORMS.
NO DRUGSTORE HOSTAGE PHOTO.
NO APPOINTMENTS.
NO MIDDLEMAN YOU ARE PAYING TO
DO SOMETHING THAT SHOULD BE
AVAILABLE TO YOU.
YOU TELL AMERICA.GOV WHAT YOU
ARE TRYING TO DO AND IT WALKS
YOU THROUGH EVERY STEP AND TELLS
YOU EXACTLY WHAT COMES NEXT.
AND THEN THERE ARE THE -- THERE
IS THIS.
REAL-TIME STATUS.
SO FOR YEARS, YOU COULD TRUCK
ANY DELIVERY LIKE A PIZZA.
MORE PRECISELY THAN YOUR
PASSPORT IN THE MAIL.
NOT ANYMORE.
YOU HAVE AN ESTIMATED DELIVERY
DATE SO YOU KNOW WHEN IT IS
COMING.
BY THE END OF 2027, OUR GOAL FOR
THE VAST MAJORITY OF AMERICANS
IS TO BE ABLE TO APPLY FOR A
PASSPORT OR PASSPORT CARD ON
AMERICA.GOV.
THE POINT OF ALL OF THIS WE ARE
DOING TODAY IS SIMPLE.
MAKE THE PROCESS MORE ACCESSIBLE
AND EASIER FOR AMERICANS.
SO WHETHER YOU LIVE IN THE
MIDDLE OF A MAJOR CITY OR YOU
LIVE IN A RURAL TOWN, YOU WILL
BE ABLE TO APPLY FROM ANYWHERE.
NOW, THERE IS ONE MORE THING.
>> HIGH ABOVE TWO AND HAVE
CENTURIES WAS THE AMERICAN
EAGLE.
AND IT HAS SEEN IT ALL.
IT WITNESSED ORDINARY MEN FIGHT
THE MOST POWERFUL EMPIRE ON
EARTH AND THEY FOUGHT FOR A
SIMPLE IDEA THAT CHANGED THE
WORLD THAT A FREE PEOPLE SHOULD
GOVERN THEMSELVES.
FROM THAT FREEDOM, A NEW NATION
ROSE AND RISE, IT DID.
WEST, INTO A VAST AND UNKNOWN
WORLD.
NORTH TOWARD THE PROMISE OF
FREEDOM ACROSS MOUNTAINS AND
PLAINS.
UNTIL STEEL RAILS FOUND IN
OCEAN.
THEN AMERICANS ROSE FROM THE
EARTH ITSELF INTO THE SKY AND
INTO BATTLE.
IT WATCHED BRAVE MEN RAISE OUR'S
FLAG ON A DISTANT ISLAND.
AND A GENERATION RAISED ITS
VOICE FOR THE PROMISES MADE AT
THE VERY BEGINNING.
THEN THE ROCKETS ROSE HIGHER
THAN ANYTHING EVER BEFORE.
BEYOND OUR LAND, BEYOND OUR
SKIES, BEYOND EARTH ITSELF, FOR
250 YEARS, WE FOUGHT FOR FREEDOM
AND CARRIED SACRED FIRE FROM
EVERY SACRED HORIZON.
NOW THAT FREEDOM IS IN YOUR
HANDS AND THE WORK IS
UNFINISHED.
DREAM WITH THE.
BUILD WITH IT.
DEFENDED, CARRY IT FURTHER
BECAUSE AMERICA WAS DESIGNED TO
RISE.
>> THAT LOOKS PRETTY GOOD.
I ACTUALLY CARRY THESE AROUND
WITH ME NOW.
THERE IT IS.
IT LOOKS EVEN BETTER IN PERSON.
THIS IS THE 2028 U.S. PASSPORT.
THE STATE DEPARTMENT WORKS
REALLY CLOSELY WITH THE NATIONAL
DESIGN STUDIO TO RETHINK IT FROM
COVER TO COVER.
BECAUSE OF PASSPORT IS MORE THAN
JUST A TRAVEL DOCUMENT.
IT IS AN EXPRESSION OF THE
UNBREAKABLE BOND BETWEEN THE
NATION AND THE CITIZEN.
A BOND BY THE WAY THAT DOES NOT
END AT THE WATER'S EDGE AT THE
BORDERS BUT ONE THAT AMERICANS
CARRY WITH THEM.
YOU CARRY THIS WITH YOU WHEN YOU
TRAVEL TO ANY CORNER AND EVERY
CORNER OF THE GLOBE.
WE FOUND ONE UNIQUELY AMERICAN
SYMBOL TO CARRY THAT IDEA FROM
BEGINNING TO END.
YOU SEE IT CARVED INTO OUR
BUILDINGS.
YOU SEE IT ON THE SHIPS TO
DEFEND OUR COUNTRY.
WE SEE IT ON OUR CURRENCY.
AND WHEN OUR FOUNDERS NEEDED A
SYMBOL OF THE COUNTRY ITSELF,
THEY PLACED IT AT THE CENTER AS
THE GREAT SEAL.
FRANKLY, THERE WAS ONLY ONE
CHOICE.
THE AMERICAN EAGLE.
THE EMBLEM OF AMERICAN STRENGTH
AND FREEDOM.
INSTANTLY RECOGNIZABLE TO
ANYONE, ANYWHERE IN THE WORLD.
THE EAGLE HAS ALWAYS BEEN ON THE
COVER OF THE PASSPORT.
WITH JOE AND HIS TEAM AT THE
DESIGN STUDIO HELPED MAKE IT
EVEN BETTER.
NOW, THAT IS THE OLD PASSPORT,
RIGHT?
THAT IS THE NEW ONE.
THE WORDS THE UNITED STATES OF
AMERICA ARE EXACTLY WHERE THEY
BELONG FIRST, RIGHT ON TOP.
THE GREAT SEAL IS LARGER AND
MORE PROMINENT AND MORE GOLD.
AND WHEN YOU OPEN THE BOOK --
WHEN YOU OPEN THE BOOK, THE
EAGLE TAKES FLIGHT.
THE EAGLE CARRIES YOU ACROSS 250
YEARS OF AMERICA.
YOU SEE IT'S SORE RIGHT FROM THE
EAGLES POINT OF VIEW ABOUT
PATRIOT STANDING IN LEXINGTON
AND PASSED A FAMILY CROSSING
WEST WITH EVERYTHING THEY OWNED
IN A WAGON.
THE MAN WHO DROVE STEEL ACROSS
THE CONTINENT.
TWO BICYCLE MECHANICS FROM OHIO
WHO TAUGHT MANKIND HOW TO FLY.
THERE ARE THE MARINES THAT
RAISED THE FLAG ON-YEAR-OLD YUME
AMERICAN HISTORY FROM THE PATRI6
TO THE PIONEERS GOING OUT INTO
THE GREAT UNKNOWN TO THE
ASTRONAUTS WHO CARRIED THE
FLAG TO THE MOON.
IT IS THE STORY OF THE GREATEST
NATION IN THE HISTORY OF THE
WORLD.
A NATION DOESN'T FROM THE VERY
BEGINNING FOR EXTRAORDINARY
THINGS.
AND THIS PASSPORT WON'T JUST
CARRY YOU.
IT WILL CARRY THAT STORY INTO
THE WORLD.
BECAUSE THIS IS ONE OF THE MOST
SECURE DOCUMENTS IN THE WORLD,
THERE ARE OBVIOUSLY THINGS I
CAN'T AND WON'T TO SHOW YOU.
BUT HERE'S WHAT I CAN SHOW YOU.
I CAN SHOW YOU THIS.
WATCH THE EAGLE AS YOU FLIP
THROUGH THE PAGES.
IT FLIES.
I THINK THAT IS PRETTY GOOD.
[APPLAUSE] I CAN SEE AMERICANS
SITTING AT AIRPORTS ALL OVER THE
WORLD LIKE, WHY DO PEOPLE KEEP
FLIPPING THROUGH THE PAGES?
IS EITHER THIS OR SOME GAME BOY
FOR YOUR KIDS TO KEEP THEM
ENTERTAINED.
THE BOOK ITSELF IS BEAUTIFUL.
IT IS INCREDIBLY SECURE.
IT FEELS SUBSTANTIAL.
AFTER PUTTING THIS MUCH STOCK
INTO THE BOOK ITSELF, WE FIGURED
THE WEIGHT ARRIVES IN YOUR HOME
SHOULD MATTER TOO.
THE PRESENTATION OF HOW IT GETS
THERE SHOULD MATTER.
SO YOU REMEMBER THIS.
I SHOULD DO THIS EARLIER.
WE ARE NOT DOING THAT ANYMORE.
SOMETHING AS IMPORTANT AND
DIGNIFIED AS UNITED STATES PASST
WILL RIDE THE WAVE EXPECTED TO.
THIS IS WHAT COMES NEXT.
[APPLAUSE] AT THE STATE
DEPARTMENT, WE ARE NOT WAITING.
WE MOVE PRETTY QUICK.
WE TRY TO MOVE FAST.
WE ARE NOT WAITING UNTIL 2027 TO
BRING YOU SOMETHING REALLY
EXCITING.
A PASSPORT APPLICATION
EXPERIENCE YOU CAN COMPLETE
ENTIRELY FROM HOME AND IN 2028
PICK A BEAUTIFUL NEW UNITED
STATES PASSPORT CARRYING 250
YEARS OF AMERICA AND IT AND OUR
GOAL IS TO MAKE PASSPORTS AND
PASSPORT CARDS ACCESSIBLE TO
MORE AMERICANS BECAUSE THE
UNITED STATES PASSPORT SAYS
SOMETHING VERY SIMPLE.
IT SAYS IT ANYWHERE IN THE
WORLD.
IT SAYS, I'M AN AMERICAN.
AND MY COUNTRY STANDS BEHIND ME.
AMERICAN CITIZENSHIP IS A SACRED
THING.
AND THE SYMBOLS AND DOCUMENTS
THAT UPHOLD IT SHOULD REFLECT
THAT.
THAT IS PRECISELY WHAT THE NEW
UNITED STATES PASSPORT WILL DO.
SO I HOPE YOU WILL GET ONE AND
THANK YOU FOR THE OPPORTUNITY TO
PRESENT THIS.
>> HELLO EVERYBODY.
HOW EXCITING WAS THIS MORNING?
DID YOU ENJOY IT?
WAS IT AMAZING?
[APPLAUSE] [CHEERING].
>> IT IS REALLY INCREDIBLE.
JUST TO SEE ALL THE HARD WORK
BEHIND THE SCENES THAT JOE AND
HIS TEAM AT THE NATIONAL DESIGN
STUDIO HAVE BEEN DOING COME TO
LIFE TODAY IS EXTRAORDINARY.
WE ARE GOING TO BREAK FOR LUNCH
AND WE WILL RECONVENE IN THIS
ROOM AT 1:00 WHEN WE HAVE A FULL
AFTERNOON OF CONVERSATION AND OF
PANELS ABOUT AI AND ENERGY
DOMINANCE AND ALL OF THE HOT
TOPICS THAT ARE IN THE NEWS
TODAY WITH CABINET OFFICIALS AND
SOME OF THE LEADING BUSINESSMEN
AND WOMEN IN THE COUNTRY RIGHT
NOW.